SWEET IS SLEEP TO ME AND EVEN MORE TO BE OF STONE,
WHILE THE WRONG AND SHAME ENDURE.
TO BE WITHOUT SIGHT OR SENSE IS A MOST HAPPY CHANGE FOR ME,
THEREFORE DO NOT ROUSE ME: HUSH! SPEAK LOW.
Confirmed MP signal
and specimen's vital signs.
Specimen is conscious.
Sedatives?
Currently being administered, but to no effect.
The specimen will awaken.
Suppress it at all costs!
Response activity levels rising.
Collecting backup data.
All staff, evacuate.
Complete.
Seal all sectors.
Please evacuate ASAP.
Wait!
In that instant,
I understood everything-
the workings of the Creator
and the totality of malevolence...
We will not be able to oppose them.
However...
we must punish them.
I can hear the heartbeat
of beginning.
Golo presents
Those of you who are model citizens,
let's throw things away.
Though they may be necessary,
be strong,
and throw away as much as you can.
Model citizens,
let's take initiative in throwing things away.
Your life will become easier
when you lessen the number of things in your life.
Those of you who are model citizens,
let's throw things away.
Though they may be necessary,
be strong-
Sorry about that.
Yes.
The arrangements have been made.
Let me see...
We'll talk about this later.
What's going on?
What has happened to force this change in my schedule?
Ultimate-level information will be disclosed.
Please hurry.
Let me ask one thing.
Yes,
I confirmed it with my own eyes.
I'm certain of it.
That is enough for me.
Leave the rest to Raul.
But! However-
By the way,
does Re-l not intend to show her face tonight again?
meditation    the heartbeat of beginning
Re-l.
Did you go to see Administrator Donov yesterday?
Forget that.
Grandfather'd just be whining as usual.
Well, he is a cloistered guy.
Iggy...
That reminds me,
the checkpoints that the Security Bureau
established throughout the city last night-
what do you think they were about?
We had to surrender information to them about
infected autoreivs which are under our jurisdiction.
But, they don't intend to tell the Intelligence Bureau anything.
Who was that new guy - Raul?
I don't like him at all.
This guy, huh.
Oh,
and the tacked-on report of the brutal homicide of a civilian...
It couldn't possibly be by a
cogito-infected autoreiv that went out of control.
Re-l...
That's enough!
Cut Turing function app from speech area.
Understood.
App has been disabled.
Please confirm.
Then take the shortest route to the Autoreiv Control Facility
in interim immigrant sectors F and G.
Confirmed.
Romdeau City...
There is no doubt
that it is our last paradise.
Within this cradle, which was built
as the planetary environment deteriorated...
life continues today as it always has.
A paradise of boredom...
Then...
you were able to confirm that the
PK-30 type that got away was infected?
I'm sorry,
Dorothy.
I'll submit a report of the escaped target.
However...
However, Intelligence Bureau staff
will be here today regarding that,
so be sure to meet with them.
Yes...
Next,
your new infection investigation.
You have been issued documents
authorizing your access to the citizen residential sector.
Don't worry.
If you do as I say,
you'll be able to become a model citizen.
Don't suck up to an Entourage.
Entourages are just autoreivs.
You must try harder to interact with people
in order to become a model citizen.
Inspector... Re-l.
We last saw each other at the interview, didn't we?
He is Vincent Law.
Vincent.
Miss!
If you'd only told me, I would've welcomed you-
She's been telling you to stop calling her that for a long time.
Um,
this is the infected autoreiv from last night.
Horrible.
With the equipment available to control unit personnel,
we can't disable them without going this far.
Is that sarcasm?
No,
I'm sorry.
This is the file.
Infection among this type has recently increased.
Analyzing.
Autoreivs infected by a virus called cogito
are said to break free of human control and acquire an ego.
Romdeau is a city with a system
deeming survival to be everything.
Even the prayers supposedly offered
by autoreivs that are prepared to die
are unnecessary factors.
Your job is to protect the citizens from these factors.
That is also the shortest path for an immigrant
to become a model citizen.
By the way, Vincent.
Y-Yes?
You're still holding onto that?
Y-Yes...
Toss anything that carries the Mosk's scent.
In the preliminary inquiry-
Analysis complete.
And?
You're in luck, Re-l.
Part of the autonomic neural file escaped infection.
I reconstituted it from mnemonic data
and got the potential escape radius.
Good.
Um...
Return to your duties.
The Entourage is waiting for you.
He kept staring at you, Re-l.
I wonder.
You'd noticed.
Vincent.
Sorry to ask this of you after an all-nighter,
but let's get you working on redeeming yourself.
It's a request to investigate a possibly infected autoreiv.
His face is that of a model citizen,
It's urgent.
the face of a person this city wants.
A boring face.
But perhaps I myself am an unnecessary factor
for looking down on them.
Let's go, Iggy.
I don't know when.
I'll leave that to you.
Sorry about that.
Please continue.
Yes.
We have expanded our search radius
to include interim immigrant sectors D, E, and F.
Armed autoreivs are patrolling the area
with the Mainland and the Island as their main focus,
but they have been unable to find the specimen.
So it is possible that it is no longer in the residential sectors.
I will see to the arrangements at once.
An abandoned Immigration Bureau facility, eh?
Several immigrants are apparently occupying it illegally.
HQ.
We have reached the projected escape radius.
Yes.
The rest will be arranged by the Bureau Chief.
The details will be reported later.
Re-l, we have orders to wait for the Security Bureau to arrive.
From the Bureau Chief-
That is...
my Mary.
I got her ID.
ED-26731.
It's a companion-type autoreiv.
Damn.
Show your immigrant ID, please.
Wh-What?
It's infected by cogito...
Re-l, what happened?
Confirmed elimination of one target.
Wait!
Iggy,
the autoreiv-
What's going on?
Iggy.
Contact the Control Division.
Have them pursue it.
Roger.
More importantly...
What was...
that?
The analysis is now complete, but...
it seems there are no symptoms indicating infection.
That's impossible.
Even yesterday, Pino-
However...
the test results
are conclusive.
Oh, yes.
To tell you the truth,
the Health and Welfare Human
Resources Division just made a decision
to finally grant me a child like I've been wanting all these years.
In that case, I feel it'd be better
to have an autoreiv that can double as a housekeeper-type
for educating and raising the child...
It is certainly true
that consumption is what model citizens should do.
However,
insofar as she is not infected,
I cannot collect her because of the regulations-
You...
are just an immigrant.
You won't do as I say, even though you're an immigrant?
Even though you're an immigrant...
I am the Citizen Security Bureau's-
You must not say bad things about immigrants,
Mother.
Mother,
you haven't cleaned yet today.
When Father comes back...
Raul.
To have this situation arise so soon
after your inauguration as the Bureau Chief
is bad luck.
On the other hand,
you may actually be a lucky man after all,
now that PROXY has awakened.
A door-to-door search operation
has been in action throughout Romdeau City
since last night, with a primary
focus on citizen residential sectors.
However, it has yet to be found.
That would mean
it has already escaped into the
immigrant sectors beyond the city's outer limits?
That would seem to be the reasonable conclusion.
Immigrants without a master...
One of them may have abetted its escape.
That is out of the question.
They do not even know of its existence.
We would like to confirm one thing.
What would that be?
Are we limited to capture only?
At this point, forty-one civilian deaths have been confirmed.
In recent years, we have had many incidents in our city
involving autoreivs infected by the cogito virus
going inexplicably berserk.
The number of victims has also
continued to increase correspondingly.
Even citizens, who are under strict information control,
will become anxious over time.
As a means of maintaining stability in the city government,
we would like permission to
eliminate it in the event of an emergency.
Raul,
don't get ahead of yourself.
Capture it without fail.
You must not kill it at any cost.
Civilian casualties are acceptable to a certain extent.
If their numbers start falling short,
we merely need to produce more.
In any case, capture it and bring it back.
Is that clear,
Raul?
One last thing:
What is "PROXY"?
Re-l,
I've already found four bodies thus far.
This must be what the Security Bureau wants to hide.
There is one more thing I found out.
The killer wasn't a cogito-infected autoreiv.
Then who?
The Security Bureau has transmitted an order.
Continuing your current actions
may violate your job regulations.
Fine, fine.
Still, though I was told to secure the crime scene,
I was not forbidden from taking a look.
Well, sure, but...
C'mon.
Let's go home before that yucky guy comes.
Anyway, seems like I'll get scolded
by Grandfather again if I go any further.
Huh?
Re-l.
Hey, what are you talking about?
No need for you to know, Iggy.
I'm very sorry,
but please submit documents to the Specialty Bureau-
Dorothy...
This destructive capability
and jumping ability demonstrated during its escape...
Neither are possible, even by high-performance autoreivs.
Isn't that right?
What could've been the purpose behind conducting research
on such a monster in utter secrecy?
The representative would not say, but...
To be quite frank,
I do not know either.
I was merely babysitting the
comatose specimen as it slept on endlessly.
However,
obtaining its abilities will have great significance...
That's what I'm beginning to think, in any case.
Chief Raul.
From the team in interim immigrant sector D.
Re-l Mayer?
Like I said, Iggy,
access HQ's databank
and put together a dossier of similar incidents.
Roger.
Grandfather's summons...
The Security Bureau's suspicious actions...
And... that...
These dots will connect somewhere; I'm sure of it.
And that was my day.
Hm?
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
With the Security Bureau out of control,
the Information Bureau's silence,
and the Entourages' manipulation...
Each dot is linked to monsters
and as they are connected,
meditation  confessions of a model citizen
the truth no one knows will manifest itself.